Register of the Louis Raemaekers Papers and Artwork
Hoover Institution Archives
Louis Raemaekers papers and artwork,
1901-1941
44001
Raemaekers, Louis, 1869-1956
13 manuscript boxes, 29 oversize boxes, 2 card file boxes, 1 album box, 4 envelopes, 2 map case drawers, 1 framed drawing (18 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Cartoons, sketches, paintings, correspondence, clippings, newspaper issues, and photographs, relating primarily to World War I. Includes anti-German World War I cartoons, and cartoons relating to interwar world politics.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired in 1944.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Searchworks at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Searchworks is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1869 April 6 Born at Roermond (Limburg), Netherlands, of a Dutch father (Josephus C. H., editor of a provincial newspaper) and a German mother
Studied art in Amsterdam, Brussels, and Paris
1892 Diploma, Art School, Amsterdam
Portrait and landscape painter; professor of drawing and architecture at Wagemingen
1902 Married Johanna Petronella van Mansvelt; had one son and two daughters
1907 First cartoons appeared in the Algemeen Handelsblad, Amsterdam
1909 February Joined the Amsterdam Telegraaf as a political cartoonist and caricaturist
1914 September Ceased all other professional activity to dedicate himself to his anti-German campaign
1915 Charged in the Dutch courts with endangering the neutrality of Holland - discharged
1915 October-Nov. First exhibit of his cartoons given at the Fine Arts Society's Galleries in London
1916 February "Manifestation Raemaekers" in Paris Presented with the Cross of the Legion of Honor
1916 Spring Moved from Harlem to Sydenham, near London, in order to supply the Allied press around the world more readily
1916 - 1918 Made frequent visits to the front in France
1917 July-December Toured the United States on the request of David Lloyd George and drew cartoons for various newspapers, most notably the Hearst papers
1919 April 7 Guest of honor at a luncheon party given by the Lord Mayor of London at the Mansion House
Inter-war period Lived in Brussels, Belgium Campaigned in favor of the League of Nations and tried to alert public opinion to the danger of Nazism to world peace
1940 June Emigrated to the United States via England
Drew weekly cartoons for the New York Herald Tribune and the afternoon tabloid PM
1956 July 26 Died at Scheveningen near The Hague, Netherlands
Scope and Content Note
The Louis Raemaekers collection, acquired in 1944, contains correspondence, writings, newspaper issues, clippings, photographs, and over 1,000 original drawings, consisting mostly of the bitingly satirical cartoons that made the Dutch artist famous worldwide.
Raemaekers joined the Amsterdam Telegraaf as a political cartoonist and caricaturist in 1907, but with the outbreak of World War I ceased all other professional activity to dedicate himself to an anti-German campaign through his cartoons. He was charged in the Dutch courts for violating the neutrality of Holland, but his work found an appreciative audience in London where it was exhibited in 1915. During the war he made frequent visits to the French front, charcoal in hand. In 1917, he toured the United States and drew cartoons for various newspapers. The inter-war period found him living in Belgium and campaigning in favor of the League of Nations and against the rising tide of Nazism. He eventually emigrated to the United States and continued his artistic career by drawing cartoons for the New York Herald Tribune and the afternoon tabloid PM
Among the papers is an extensive correspondence series, which reflects Raemaekers' activism and contacts with many heads of state, ministers, government agencies, relief organizations, and veterans' associations. Also noteworthy are scrapbooks of clippings relating to Raemaekers' life and work. The speeches and writings series is very small, but does contain some interesting letters to the editor and the speech he delivered before the Lord Mayor of London in 1919.
In 2001, thanks to the generous support of the Mericos Foundation, Raemaekers' artwork was re-housed and preservation treatment provided with the assistance of the staff of the Fine Arts Museums of San Francisco. The drawings can now be safely used for research. The re-housing effort uncovered many titles previously hidden by matting, and those were incorporated into a revised and expanded register.
Raemaekers' handwriting is often difficult to decipher, so the titles given in the finding aid may not always exactly correspond to those on his artwork. In addition, minor grammar and spelling mistakes were corrected.
Ariane de Ranitz, who had researched the Raemaekers collection at the Hoover Institution Archives to write her book, Met een pen en een potlood als wapen (with a pen and a pencil as weapons), assisted the Archives staff with Dutch language titles.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Propaganda, Anti-German.; World politics-20th century--Caricatures and cartoons.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Humor, caricatures, etc.; World War, 1914-1918--Propaganda.; Germany.; Netherlands.
Container List
- Biographical File, 1915-1939. (Box 1)
  Biographical data, club membership cards, invitations, and programs, menus, table sitting arrangements, etc. of various celebrations that were given in Louis Raemaekers' honor or that he was invited to, arranged alphabetically
  - Biographical data given by Louis Raemaekers (Folder 1: 1)
  - Club membership cards, United States, 1917 (Folder 1: 2)
  - Invitations to luncheons, galas, etc., including exhibit catalogs
    - Given in honor of Louis Raemaekers (Folder 1: 3)
    - To which he was invited (Folder 1: 4)
  - Subject file
    - Commemoration Meeting and Honorary Graduation, University of Glasgow, 1922 June 22 (Folder 1: 5)
    - Dinner given in honor of Louis Raemaekers by the Cercle de l'U.M.A., Liège, 1921 December 22 (Folder 1: 6)
    - Luncheons given in honor of Louis Raemaekers
      - By the London Press, 1915 December 8 (Folder 1: 7)
      - By the Lord Mayor of London, 1919 April 7 (Folder 1: 8)
    - "Manifestation Raemaekers," Paris, 1916 February (Folder 1: 9)
- Correspondence, 1901-1939. (Box 1-8)
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
  - Unidentified (Folder 1: 10)
  - General (Folder 1: 11-30)
  - A. J. Woodruff and Co., New York, 1917 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Aberconway, Laura, 1925 (Folder 2: 2)
  - Action et Civilisation, Brussels, 1932-1933 (Folder 2: 3)
  - Adam, J. P., 1919 (Folder 2: 4)
  - Adatci, M., 1933-1934 (Folder 2: 5)
  - Adventurer's Club, New York, 1917 (Folder 2: 6)
  - Advertising Club of Baltimore, n.d. (Folder 2: 7)
  - Ailly, A. J. d', 1914 (Folder 2: 8)
  - Air Services, London., See Drogheda, Countess Kathleen
  - Albert I, King of the Belgians (1876-1965), 1917-1929 (Folder 2: 9)
  - Album Louis Raemaekers (Dessins d'un neutre), Amsterdam, 1915 (Folder 2: 10)
  - Aldwych Theatre, London, n.d. (Folder 2: 11)
  - Alexander, King of Yugoslavia, n.d. (Folder 2: 12)
  - Algemeen Handelsblad, Amsterdam, 1909-1915 (Folder 2: 13)
  - Algemeene Nederlandsche Vrouwen Vredebond, Amsterdam, 1935 (Folder 2: 14)
  - Allizé, Henri and Mme, 1915-1919 (Folder 2: 15)
  - Althuizen, N. M., 1915-1929 (Folder 2: 16)
  - American Art Student, New York, 1917 (Folder 2: 17)
  - American "Blue Shirts," 1932 (Folder 2: 18)
  - American Club of Brussels, 1929-1937 (Folder 2: 19)
  - Amis des Artistes, Paris, 1915 (Folder 2: 20)
  - Ansingh, Lizzy, 1914-1937 (Folder 2: 21)
  - Armenian Refugees Fund, London, 1916-1917 (Folder 2: 22)
  - Armenraad., See Federatie van Instellingen voor Kinderbescherming Jack
  - Arsac, d' (Le Soir,) 1920-1934 (Folder 2: 23)
  - Art-Workers' Guild, London, 1916 (Folder 2: 24)
  - Artists Aid to the Red Cross, Service Bureau, Chicago, 1917 (Folder 2: 25)
  - Arts Club, London, 1916-1919 (Folder 2: 26)
  - Asquith, Herbert Henry, 1916-1917 (Folder 2: 27)
  - Association Littéraire et Artistique Internationale, Paris, 1926 (Folder 2: 28)
  - Association Syndicale de la Presse Etrangère, Paris, 1916 (Folder 2: 29)
  - Associazione della Stampa Estera, Rome, 1917 (Folder 2: 30)
  - Automobiles Hotchkiss, Brussels, 1933-1936 (Folder 2: 31)
  - Baart de la Faille, J., 1914-1927 (Folder 2: 32)
  - Baird, Jaimes, 1916-1919 (Folder 2: 33)
  - Balkuizen van den Brink, L. W., 1917-1923 (Folder 2: 34)
  - Bartlett, Paul W., 1918 (Folder 2: 35)
  - Bastien, Alfred, n.d. (Folder 2: 36)
  - Beard, A. M., 1916 (Folder 2: 37)
  - Bearsted, Lord, n.d. (Folder 2: 38)
  - Beatrice, Consort of Henry, Prince of Battenberg (1857-1944), 1918-1919 (Folder 2: 39)
  - Been, Jozeph, 1910 (Folder 2: 40)
  - Beer, Taco G. de, 1915 (Folder 2: 41)
  - Belgian Orphan Fund, London, 1917 (Folder 2: 42)
  - Belgian Relief Fund, London, n.d. (Folder 2: 43)
  - Belgium. Ministère des Sciences et des Arts, 1924 (Folder 2: 44)
  - Belloc, H., 1924 (Folder 2: 45)
  - Bendt, P. F., 1915 (Folder 2: 46)
  - Benjamin, Henri, 1923 (Folder 2: 47)
  - Berlekom, Marie Berdenis van, 1914-1915 (Folder 2: 48)
  - Besuijen, J., 1914 (Folder 2: 49)
  - Bevervoorde van Rappard, A. Louise van, 1916-1918 (Folder 2: 50)
  - Bibliographie nationale, Brussels, 1937 (Folder 2: 51)
  - Bibliothèque d'Art et d'Archéologie, Paris, 1916 (Folder 2: 52)
  - Blok, P. J., 1919 (Folder 2: 53)
  - Blumberger, M. T., 1934 (Folder 2: 54)
  - Boer van Ryk, Esther de, 1923 (Folder 2: 55)
  - Boissevain, A. G., See Algemeen Handelsblad
  - Bok, Edward, 1917 (Folder 2: 56)
  - Booth, Mary, 1916 (Folder 2: 57)
  - Borel, Henri, 1902-1914 (Folder 2: 58)
  - Borgesius, A. M., 1910 (Folder 2: 59)
  - Botha, Louis, General, 1916 (Folder 2: 60)
  - Bour, Jetty, n.d. (Folder 2: 61)
  - Bourgeois, Léon, 1920 (Folder 2: 62)
  - Bradley, L. D., 1915 (Folder 2: 63)
  - Bramson, Arn, 1915 (Folder 2: 64)
  - Bredius, 1910 (Folder 2: 65)
  - Briand, Aristide, 1932 (Folder 2: 66)
  - Brisbane, A., 1917 (Folder 2: 67)
  - Britannia (The Women's Social and Political Union), London, 1915 (Folder 2: 68)
  - British Ambulance Committee., See Portland, Duke and Duchess of
  - British Mission, Paris, 1918 (Folder 2: 69)
  - British Recruiting Mission, Boston, 1917 (Folder 2: 70)
  - British Red Cross, London, 1916-1917., See also Northcliffe, Mary, Lady (Folder 2: 71)
  - British Women War Workers, Mexico City, 1917 (Folder 2: 72)
  - Broderick, J. Joyce., See Canadian Club of Hamilton
  - Brown Robertson Co., New York, 1919 (Folder 2: 73)
  - Bulsing van Besouw, B., n.d. (Folder 2: 74)
  - Burdon-Muller, Constance, n.d. (Folder 2: 75)
  - Burnham, 1920 (Folder 2: 76)
  - Buysse, Cyriel, 1927 (Folder 2: 77)
  - Bylandt, A. van, 1917 (Folder 2: 78)
  - Bylandt, O. van, 1915 (Folder 2: 79)
  - Byrne, James, 1917 (Folder 2: 80)
  - Caisse Patronale, Brussels, 1933-1935 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Cambon, Paul, 1916-1919 (Folder 3: 2)
  - Campbell, Fred, 1917-1924 (Folder 3: 3)
  - Campbell, Ian M., 1931-1936 (Folder 3: 4)
  - Canadian Club of Hamilton, Ontario, 1917 (Folder 3: 5)
  - Canadian News, London, 1916 (Folder 3: 6)
  - Capel, Arthur, 1917 (Folder 3: 7)
  - Carbonnel, P. de, n.d. (Folder 3: 8)
  - Cartier, E. de, Baron, 1935 (Folder 3: 9)
  - Carton de Wiart, Baron, 1918-1926 (Folder 3: 10)
  - Carver, Clifford N., 1917-1922 (Folder 3: 11)
  - Castle, William R., Jr., 1917-1919 (Folder 3: 12)
  - Cecil, Robert, Lord, 1921-1931 (Folder 3: 13)
  - Centennial Club, Nashville, 1917 (Folder 3: 14)
  - Central Press, Ltd., See Estrange, Guy l'
  - Century Co., New York, 1923 (Folder 3: 15)
  - Cercle Artistique et Littéraire de Bruxelles, Brussels, 1922 (Folder 3: 16)
  - Churchill, Winston, 1932-1938 (Folder 3: 17)
  - Chute, Margaret, 1917 (Folder 3: 18)
  - Cockerell, Sydney C., 1917 (Folder 3: 19)
  - Cohen, Stuart, 1915-1916 (Folder 3: 20)
  - Colijn, H., 1928 (Folder 3: 21)
  - Colquhoun Club, London, 1917 (Folder 3: 22)
  - Comité National de Secours, Brussels, 1935 (Folder 3: 23)
  - Comité Officiel Belge pour l'Angleterre, London, 1915 (Folder 3: 24)
  - Comité Tegen de Joden-Ontrechting, Amsterdam, 1933 (Folder 3: 25)
  - Comité voor Bijzondere Joodsche Belangen, Amsterdam, 1934 (Folder 3: 26)
  - Compagnies Belges d'Assurances Générales, Antwerp, 1935 (Folder 3: 27)
  - Corbett-Smith, A., Major, 1916-1918 (Folder 3: 28)
  - Corri, Ghita, 1916-1918 (Folder 3: 29)
  - Coudurier de Chassaigne, J., 1916 (Folder 3: 30)
  - Crédit Mutuel Hypothécaire, Brussels, 1930-1936 (Folder 3: 31)
  - Creveld, A., 1914 (Folder 3: 32)
  - Croisade des Femmes Françaises, Paris, 1915 (Folder 3: 33)
  - Curzon, George, Lord, 1915 (Folder 3: 34)
  - Cuypers, Dr., 1911-1915 (Folder 3: 35)
  - Cuypers, Hubert, Jr., 1911-1936 (Folder 3: 36)
  - Daily Chronicle, London, 1915-1918 (Folder 3: 37)
  - Daily Mail, London, 1915-1917., See also the Daily Chronicle (Folder 3: 38)
  - Dake, C. L., n.d. (Folder 3: 39)
  - Dam, J. van, 1914 (Folder 3: 40)
  - Davray, Henry D. (The Anglo-French Society, London), 1921 (Folder 3: 41)
  - Deen, Jacques, 1914 (Folder 3: 42)
  - Delano, William Adams, 1936 (Folder 3: 43)
  - Delzaert, P., See Crédit Mutuel Hypothécaire
  - Destrée, Jules, n.d. (Folder 3: 44)
  - Deterding, H. W. A., 1930-1937 (Folder 3: 45)
  - Diepenbrock, A., 1915 (Folder 3: 46)
  - Dieren, Joseph van, 1915 (Folder 3: 47)
  - Dijk, H. C. J. M. van, 1932-1933 (Folder 3: 48)
  - Dowsing, William, 1919 (Folder 3: 49)
  - Drage, Geoffrey, 1919 (Folder 3: 50)
  - Drake, Tracy(?), n.d. (Folder 3: 51)
  - Dreyfus, Emma Price, n.d. (Folder 3: 52)
  - Driesen, G., 1935 (Folder 3: 53)
  - Drion, F. J. W., 1926-1930 (Folder 3: 54)
  - Drogheda, Kathleen, Countess, 1916-1917 (Folder 3: 55)
  - Dublin National Library, 1931 (Folder 3: 56)
  - Dumolin, Ernest, 1935 (Folder 3: 57)
  - Dumolin, Prospère, 1935 (Folder 3: 58)
  - Dunlop, H., 1930-1933 (Folder 3: 59)
  - Dunsany, 1919 (Folder 3: 60)
  - Dutch delegation to the League of Nations, Geneva, 1927 (Folder 3: 61)
  - Duveen, Charles W., 1917 (Folder 3: 62)
  - Eeden, Frederik van, 1915-1917 (Folder 3: 63)
  - Eeghen, Tyo H. van, 1917-1923 (Folder 3: 64)
  - Eilers, B. P., 1929 (Folder 3: 65)
  - Elisabeth, Consort of Albert I, King of the Belgians (1876-1965), 1927-1934 (Folder 3: 66)
  - Elout, C. K., 1910-1916 (Folder 3: 67)
  - Embden, D. van, 1914 (Folder 3: 68)
  - Emden, Frieda van, n.d. (Folder 3: 69)
  - Enthoven-Thomas, E., 1916 (Folder 3: 70)
  - Estrange, Guy L', 1934-1935 (Folder 3: 71)
  - Federatie van Instellingen voor Kinderbescherming, Amsterdam, 1934-1935 (Folder 3: 72)
  - Fédération Interalliée des Anciens Combattants, Brussels, 1932 (Folder 3: 73)
  - Feith, Jan, 1914-1915 (Folder 3: 74)
  - Ferwerda, B., 1914 (Folder 3: 75)
  - Field, Deha S., n.d. (Folder 3: 76)
  - Fine Art Society, London, 1915-1924 (Folder 3: 77)
  - First Edition Club., See Saintsbury Club
  - Fleming, Hugh, n.d. (Folder 3: 78)
  - Forain, J. L., 1915 (Folder 3: 79)
  - Forest, Julia de, n.d. (Folder 3: 80)
  - Foster(?), Margaret R., n.d. (Folder 3: 81)
  - Frampton, George, 1919 (Folder 3: 82)
  - France. Ambassade (Belgium), 1925-1930 (Folder 3: 83)
  - France. Légation (Netherlands), 1929-1930 (Folder 3: 84)
  - France. Ministère de la Guerre, Paris, n.d. (Folder 3: 85)
  - France. Ministère des Affaires Etrangères, Paris, 1916 (Folder 3: 86)
  - Frazer, Lily, Lady, 1917 (Folder 3: 87)
  - French Red Cross, London Committee, 1917 (Folder 3: 88)
  - Friend, Leon, 1933-1936 (Folder 3: 89)
  - Furnée, J. L., 1915 (Folder 3: 90)
  - Fusilier, Jan, n.d. (Folder 3: 91)
  - Galeries Georges Petit, Paris, 1916 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Garvin (The Observer), 1938 (Folder 4: 2)
  - Gazette de Hollande, The Hague., See Drion, F. J. W.
  - Gerhard, W., 1915 (Folder 4: 3)
  - Gerlacke, A. de, 1915 (Folder 4: 4)
  - Geyl, P., 1917-1919 (Folder 4: 5)
  - Gibb, Dorothea, Lady, 1916 (Folder 4: 6)
  - Gibson, C., 1920-1923 (Folder 4: 7)
  - Gibson, Hugh S., 1929-1937 (Folder 4: 8)
  - Gignilliant, L. R., 1924-1937 (Folder 4: 9)
  - Giran, Etienne, 1914-1935 (Folder 4: 10)
  - Glasgow University, 1922 (Folder 4: 11)
  - Goeijen, F. M. de, 1924 (Folder 4: 12)
  - Goeijen, John A. de, 1922-1923 (Folder 4: 13)
  - Golder, James, 1928 (Folder 4: 14)
  - Gordon, Winifred, 1929 (Folder 4: 15)
  - Grand Carteret, John, 1914-1916 (Folder 4: 16)
  - Gray, Alexander, 1914 (Folder 4: 17)
  - Great Britain. War Office, London, 1915 (Folder 4: 18)
  - Great Britain. War Trade Intelligence Department. (Folder 4: 19)
    - Advisory Committee on Dutch and Dutch Colonial Matters, London, 1917
  - Green, S. D. (Senior High School, Trenton, N.J.), 1923-1924 (Folder 4: 20)
  - Greenway, Cornelius, Reverend, 1927 (Folder 4: 21)
  - Grève, J. de, 1935 (Folder 4: 22)
  - Greville, Lady, 1917 (Folder 4: 23)
  - Grey of Fallodon, Pamela, Lady, 1925., See also League of Nations Union (Folder 4: 24)
  - Groene Amsterdammer, Amsterdam, 1935-1936 (Folder 4: 25)
  - Groot, G. de, 1917 (Folder 4: 26)
  - Grosvenor, Florence, 1918 (Folder 4: 27)
  - Grouitch, Mabel S., 1931-1936 (Folder 4: 28)
  - Grouitch, Slavko, 1931-1934 (Folder 4: 29)
  - Grunne, Eugene de, Count, 1929 (Folder 4: 30)
  - Grunne, Guillaume de, Count, 1915-1927 (Folder 4: 31)
  - Guerre des Nations, Paris, 1915 (Folder 4: 32)
  - Guest, S. (Wellington House, London), 1916-1918 (Folder 4: 33)
  - Hageman, F., 1914 (Folder 4: 34)
  - Hall, W. Reginald, Rear Admiral, 1917-1923 (Folder 4: 35)
  - Hamel, J. A. van, 1915-1922 (Folder 4: 36)
  - Harden, Maximillian G., 1924-1925 (Folder 4: 37)
  - Harrison, Frederic, 1918 (Folder 4: 38)
  - Haverman, H. J., 1915 (Folder 4: 39)
  - Havlich, 1929-1930 (Folder 4: 40)
  - Hazon de Saint-Firmin, Jane d', 1919-1936 (Folder 4: 41)
  - Heemstra, Ella Ruston-van, 1934 (Folder 4: 42)
  - Hendriks, A., 1919 (Folder 4: 43)
  - Hermans, L., n.d. (Folder 4: 44)
  - Hermite, L., 1923 (Folder 4: 45)
  - Herriot, Edouard (?), 1932 (Folder 4: 46)
  - Herthe, Louis and Eleanor, 1929-1933 (Folder 4: 47)
  - Hesselink (?) van Suchtelen, F., 1915 (Folder 4: 48)
  - Hoeven Leonard, J. van der, 1915-1916 (Folder 4: 49)
  - Holdert, F. M. J. (De Telegraaf), 1915-1924., See also Schröder, J. C. (Folder 4: 50)
  - Holdert, H. M. C., 1919-1930 (Folder 4: 51)
  - Hollister, Paul, n.d. (Folder 4: 52)
  - Hollman, J., 1915-1917 (Folder 4: 53)
  - Hoogstraten, Chrétien van, 1916 (Folder 4: 54)
  - Hove, Jan ten, 1914-1924 (Folder 4: 55)
  - Hulzen, G. van (Holland Express), 1910 (Folder 4: 56)
  - Huysmans, Camille, 1933 (Folder 4: 57)
  - Hyldert-Mayer, Lotte, 1913 (Folder 4: 58)
  - Hymans, Paul, 1920-1930 (Folder 4: 59)
  - Institut für Zeitungswissenschaft, Berlin, 1936 (Folder 4: 60)
  - International Mark Twain Society, Webster Groves, Missouri, 1937 (Folder 4: 61)
  - International News Service., See Nash's Magazine
  - Ireland. Legation (France), 1934 (Folder 4: 62)
  - Italy. Ambasciàta (Great Britain), n.d. (Folder 4: 63)
  - Italy. LegaziÓne (Netherlands), (Francesco Barbaro), 1927-1928 (Folder 4: 64)
  - Italy. Ministero della Pubblica Istruzione, Rome, 1927 (Folder 4: 65)
  - Jansen, R., 1915 (Folder 4: 66)
  - Jelgersma, D. G., 1917 (Folder 4: 67)
  - Jewish Daily Bulletin, New York, 1933 (Folder 4: 68)
  - Johnson, Burges., See National Security League
  - Joodsche Invalide, Amsterdam, 1934 (Folder 4: 69)
  - Journal, Le, Paris, 1917 (Folder 4: 70)
  - Jouvenel, 1928 (Folder 4: 71)
  - Jusserand, Jean Jules, 1915-1917 (Folder 4: 72)
  - Justet, Louis, 1915 (Folder 4: 73)
  - Kamer, B. W. van de, 1914-1915 (Folder 4: 74)
  - Kan, P. T. L., 1923 (Folder 4: 75)
  - Kappeyne van de Coppello, J., 1915-1916 (Folder 4: 76)
  - Kesteloot, J., 1914 (Folder 4: 77)
  - Ketelaar-Van Gogh, M., 1927-1932 (Folder 4: 78)
  - Kiewiet de Jonge, H. J., 1928 (Folder 4: 79)
  - Kingston, Lisette, n.d. (Folder 4: 80)
  - Kipling, Rudyard, 1916-1918 (Folder 4: 81)
  - Kitcat, Mabel, 1916-1919 (Folder 4: 82)
  - Klaasen, Anna, 1935 (Folder 4: 83)
  - Klare, W. B., 1914 (Folder 4: 84)
  - Knipping, V., 1915 (Folder 4: 85)
  - Knol, B., 1934 (Folder 4: 86)
  - Koninklijke Luchtvaart Maatschappij voor Nederland en Kolonien N. V., The Hague, 1932 (Folder 4: 87)
  - Koninklijke-Nederlandsche Zwen Bond, Amsterdam, 1935 (Folder 4: 88)
  - Koopman, Jules, 1916 (Folder 4: 89)
  - Koster, Edward B., 1914 (Folder 4: 90)
  - Kuiler, Kor, 1928-1929 (Folder 4: 91)
  - Kuyper, Albert de, 1929 (Folder 4: 92)
  - Lambotte, Paul, 1918-1934 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Lane, John, 1917-1919 (Folder 5: 2)
  - Lansing, Robert, 1919 (Folder 5: 3)
  - Latvia. Legation (Belgium), 1928-1930 (Folder 5: 4)
  - Laughlin, Irwin, 1917 (Folder 5: 5)
  - Lautrec, Adrienne de, 1915 (Folder 5: 6)
  - Lea, John., See Walker Art Gallery, Liverpool
  - League of Nations Union, London, 1925-1926 (Folder 5: 7)
  - Leandre, Charles, n.d. (Folder 5: 8)
  - Lecture Agency, Ltd., London, 1916 (Folder 5: 9)
  - Leeds. Lord Mayor, 1918 (Folder 5: 10)
  - Leeds Luncheon Club, 1918 (Folder 5: 11)
  - Levy, Bernard, 1932 (Folder 5: 12)
  - Liberty Loan Committee, New York and Chicago, 1917 (Folder 5: 13)
  - Library of J. Pierpont Morgan, New York, 1918-1919 (Folder 5: 14)
  - Liège (Belgium). Bourgmestre, 1933-1934 (Folder 5: 15)
  - Ligue des Pays Neutres pour la Défense du Droit des Gens, Paris, 1916-1918 (Folder 5: 16)
  - Ligue des Poilus de France en Belgique, Brussels, 1925., See also Poilus de France (Folder 5: 17)
  - Ligue Nationale Belge contre le Péril Vénérien, Brussels, n.d. (Folder 5: 18)
  - Lioni, Sam, 1915 (Folder 5: 19)
  - Lithuania. Legation (Belgium), 1934 (Folder 5: 20)
  - Liverpool (England). Lord Mayor, 1916-1917 (Folder 5: 21)
  - Lloyd George, David, 1916-1919 (Folder 5: 22)
  - Locker Lampson, O., 1936 (Folder 5: 23)
  - Loder, J., 1935 (Folder 5: 24)
  - London. Lord Mayor, 1919 (Folder 5: 25)
  - Long, John Luther, n.d. (Folder 5: 26)
  - Loo, J. van, Brigadier, 1935-1936 (Folder 5: 27)
  - Loon, Hendrik Willem van, 1916 (Folder 5: 28)
  - Loti, Pierre, 1915 (Folder 5: 29)
  - Loudon, J., 1915-1918 (Folder 5: 30)
  - Louter, J. de, 1927-1929 (Folder 5: 31)
  - Louther, Alice, 1916 (Folder 5: 32)
  - Loyson, Paul Hyacinthe, 1915 (Folder 5: 33)
  - Luns, Huib, 1934 (Folder 5: 34)
  - Luyten, J., 1914 (Folder 5: 35)
  - McCormick and Co., Baltimore, 1917 (Folder 5: 36)
  - McDonald, D. C., 1927 (Folder 5: 37)
  - Macdonogh, George, Lieutenant General, 1918 (Folder 5: 38)
  - McGaw, 1934-1936 (Folder 5: 39)
  - McLaughlin, R. J., 1917 (Folder 5: 40)
  - Malvezzi de Medici, A., 1929 (Folder 5: 41)
  - Manassen, B., 1935 (Folder 5: 42)
  - Manchester Guardian, Manchester, 1933 (Folder 5: 43)
  - Mann, Arthur, 1917 (Folder 5: 44)
  - Marchant, H. P., 1915-1934 (Folder 5: 45)
  - Mars, P. C., 1919 (Folder 5: 46)
  - Marshall, Archibald, 1920 (Folder 5: 47)
  - Masson, F., 1922 (Folder 5: 48)
  - Mastenbroek, J. H., 1929 (Folder 5: 49)
  - Matin, Le, Paris, 1931-1935 (Folder 5: 50)
  - Mauve, A. R., n.d. (Folder 5: 51)
  - Mayer, Adolf, 1914 (Folder 5: 52)
  - Mayer, Henri, 1929 (Folder 5: 53)
  - Mees, J., 1933 (Folder 5: 54)